Bhumika Mittal

■ mittalbhumika7@gmail.com | mittalbhumika7 | ↑ bhumikamittal7 | ♦ bhumikamittal.in

Research Interest

My research interests include **cryptography** and **computational complexity**, with a focus on lattice-based cryptography. In particular, I am working on the fine-grained complexity of lattice problems and pre-image samplable trapdoor functions. I am also interested in quantum cryptography and quantum computing.

EDUCATION

Ashoka University Sonipat, India

Diploma in Advanced Studies and Research, Computer Science

2024 - Present

Thesis: Threshold Pre-Image Samplable Trapdoor Functions

 $Bachelor\ of\ Science\ (Honours),\ Computer\ Science;\ CGPA:\ 3.90/4.00$

2021 - 2024

Minors in Mathematics, and Entrepreneurial Leadership & Strategy

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

IIT Delhi New Delhi, India

Research Assistant Sept 2024 - Present

- Developing an efficient reduction from the Closest Vector Problem to Weighted Max-SAT for even norms
- Implementing the designed encoding using the RC2 MaxSAT solver to evaluate its efficiency

Max Planck Institute for Software Systems

Saarbrücken, Germany

Visiting Research Fellow

May 2024 - Aug 2024

- Proposed the PACT metric for evaluating phase-concurrent execution efficiency; analyzed SOTA graph systems
- Designed and implemented a system optimizing scans and updates, achieving improved throughput and efficiency

Centre for Artificial Intelligence and Robotics, DRDO

New Delhi, India

Research Intern

Nov 2023 - May 2024

- Designed and implemented an indigenous lattice-based post-quantum public key encryption and signature scheme
- Conducted a study on NIST PQC finalists, contributing to the security framework against algebraic attacks

IIT Gandhinagar

Gandhinagar, India

Research Assistant

May 2023 - Sept 2023

- Analyzed the transformer architecture (BERT) to identify hardware-level operations for efficient inference
- Proposed an architecture to reduce power consumption; used Timeloop-Accelergy for energy and latency estimates

Publications and Expositions

Vortex: Efficient Adaptive Graph Store

Seemant Achari, Bhumika Mittal, Ashvin Goel, Laurent Bindschaedler

SEAL-ME: Secure, Energy-Efficient Accelerator Design for Language Models

in review

Tom Glint, Bhumika Mittal, Santripta Sharma, Abdul Ronak, Aravind Krishna, Joycee Mekie

On the Existence of Balanced Generalized de Bruijn Sequences

Discrete Mathematics Journal

Bhumika Mittal, Haran Mouli, Eric Tang, Matthew Baker

April 2023

Relevant Coursework

Lattice-based Cryptography, SAT Solvers, Computer Security and Privacy, Elliptic Curves and Cryptography, Quantum Computing, Investigation of Dilithium, Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies, Theory of Computation

Honors and Awards

- 2024 Summa Cum Laude, Ashoka University
- 2024 Silver Medalist, Department of Computer Science, Ashoka University
- 2024 Builder's Award for Service Excellence, Department of Computer Science, Ashoka University
- 2022 Undergraduate Research Excellence Award, Department of Mathematics, Ashoka University
- 2021-24 **Dean's List** (every semester), Ashoka University

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Ashoka University Sonipat, India

 $7 \times Teaching Assistant$

- Teaching Assistant for multiple courses like Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics (student feedback: 4.88/5)
- Facilitated the Science Communication module at the Lodha Genius Program for 200+ high school students

Lehigh University

Bethlehem, US

Exchange Student

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Consulted for Global Good Fund, establishing metrics to evaluate ESG impact, measure non-monetary outcomes
- Strategized optimal investment approaches to enhance ESG goals and ensure measurable financial outcomes

Plaksha University

Mohali, India

Instructor

April 2023 - June 2023

- \bullet Taught a Microcontrollers course to 200+ high school students through IoT projects using ESP32 chipset
- Designed a game development module, building 5 mathematical and hardware games for hands-on learning

WebVeda Remote

Tech and Product Manager

Feb 2021 - April 2022

Aug 2022 - May 2024

- Ideated and developed the platform, scaling to 300k learners and generating \$1M revenue within 10 months.
- Managed tech infrastructure, including payment gateways, email integration, and other critical system components.

OTHER ACTIVITIES

Mathematics for post-quantum cryptanalysis Selected Student Attendee	Eötvös Loránd University August 2024
Summer Research Institute on Systems, Security, and Privacy Participant	EPFL July 2024
Undergrad Architecture Mentoring Workshop (uArch) Full Grant Recipient	ISCA 2024, Argentina June 2024
Workshop on Lattice-based Post-quantum Cryptography Speaker, Co-organiser	Ashoka University $April\ 2024$
Academic Affairs Board Computer Science Student Representative	Ashoka University May 2023 – May 2024
IEEE Ashoka Student Branch Director of Tech	Ashoka University Aug 2023 – May 2024
Computer Science Society	Ashoka University

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Student Advisor, President

Programming & Development: C/C++, Python, Solidity, Assembly, Git, Qiskit, Hyperledger Fabric

Hardware & Tools: Timeloop/Accelergy, ESP32, Raspberry Pi Pico, LATEX, Docker